lesmillsondemand.com 2017-02-19

# Privacy Policy – Les Mills

Les Mills International Limited (jointly referred to as LMI) operates the lesmills.com website (including all content and functionality available through the lesmills.com domain name and any country or region specific domains or sub domains) (jointly referred to as the “Site”). LMI is committed to ensuring the privacy and protection of information users enter into the Site. The following privacy policy governs LMI’s practices for information collection, use and retention on the Site. It should be read with:

(1) LMI’s standard terms and conditions of use of the Site (“Terms of Use”), found here  
(2) LMI’s online community terms of use (“Online Community Terms of Use”) found [here](https://www.lesmills.com/global/community/Community-Terms-of-Use.aspx); and   
(3) Any other policy developed by LMI from time to time and notified on the Site or any part of the Site.

In this policy:

  * "we" or "LMI" means Les Mills International Limited or any Les Mills company subsidiary or authorised distributor
  * "you" means you, the person using our services, or visiting the Site
  * "services" means all goods or services we provide to you, including providing you with access to the Site.

**Consent to collection, retention and use of information**

You agree that we may collect, retain and use information about you in accordance with this Privacy Policy. You may decline to provide any information to us. However, if you do not, our ability to provide you with some or all of our services may be impaired.

**Types of Information Collected**

As you navigate within the Site, we automatically track, collect and store information about you, your computer, PDA, telephone or other voice Internet portals. This information may include some or all of the following information about you and your visit:

  * the IP address of your machine when connected to the Internet and the domain name from which you are accessing the Internet
  * the operating system and the browser your computer uses, and any search engine you are using
  * the date and time you are visiting
  * the URLs of the pages you visit
  * if you provide them, your name, email address, physical address or location and other personal data

**Purpose for which Information is Collected and Use of Information**

You hereby expressly agree that we may use the information we collect to tailor your experience on the Site, for editorial and feedback purposes, for marketing and promotional purposes, for statistical analysis of users' behaviour, for product development, for content improvement and to inform advertisers or other interested parties of how may visitors have seen or clicked on the Site. Although we may publish aggregated information about usage patterns, we do not disclose information about individuals except as set out below. We do not sell information that identifies you personally. We may gather more extensive information if we believe it is necessary, for example, to address any security issues. If we think it is necessary, we can disclose information to relevant law enforcement authorities, such as the police.

LMI will not provide or release your personal information to a third party unless you have opted-in for a promotion. You agree that LMI may send you information on forthcoming promotions or services unless you have specifically opted-out of receiving such information. We provide you with a facility by which to do so.

We may, without specific or further notice to you, release information about you when we believe such disclosure is appropriate: for example, to protect the rights, property or safety of LMI, the Site, our users or others; enforce our terms and conditions of use; provide the services you directly request from us through the Site; comply with law, a court order or other legal process; in the course of responding to any claim by a third party that any user is using the functionality or services provided through the Site in connection with an infringing, illegal or improper activity or that data placed on the Site infringes rights of any third party; in response to a request for identification in connection with a claim of copyright or trademark infringement by you; to an affiliate or service provider engaged to maintain or host the Site, subject to that party's agreement to honour this Privacy Policy.

**Retention of Information**

We may hold information you provide to us, share it with our affiliates, employees and contractors, credit reference agencies and collection agencies. This enables us to:  
provide services to you;

  * send you bills and recover money you owe to us;
  * keep you informed of services available to you from us and other people;
  * exercise any lawful right any of us has.

**Children's Privacy**

LMI does not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13 and does not target the Site to children under 13. We encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children’s online activities and interests.

**Cookies**

A "cookie" is a file that allows us to track and target the interests of Site users. We may use cookies to keep track of pending transactions, deliver content that is specific to your interests, save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit the Site, and for other lawful purposes consistent with this Privacy Policy. The Site may place a cookie on the hard drive of your computer and your browser may accept small identifying files from our system. While we recommend that you enable cookies on your browser in order to enjoy all the features of the Site, the decision remains in your hands. Note that your browser may decline the cookie if it is set up to do so, but this may limit the functionality of the Site.

**Linked Sites**

The Site may contain links to other websites. We are not responsible for the reliability of the content or privacy practices of such other websites.

**Public Forums**

We may provide you with chat features, instant messaging, message boards, community forums and/or news groups through the Online Community or otherwise. Please remember that any information that you disclose in the Online Community or other public areas of the Site will become public information, and become accessible to all other members of the Online Community and the public. We do not intend (but reserve the right) to monitor, moderate or screen the contents of user postings. We bear no responsibility for any such content and you should be cautious when considering whether to disclose your personal information in the Online Community or any public or private forums.

**Security**

The Site has security measures to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of information contained within it. We have put in place reasonable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect. These measures may or may not be vulnerable to hacking, and we do not guarantee complete security.

**Lost or Stolen Information**

You must notify us promptly if your user name or password is lost, stolen or used without permission. Upon notice, we will cancel that user name or password and update our records accordingly.

**Opt-Out Option**

We provide you with the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communication from us or our affiliates when we request information from you. You may send a request to remove your information from our database, stop future communication, limit the use of your information, or to review and modify information that you may have previously provided using the contact information provided in the "Contact Us" section below.

**Access to Your Personal Information**

You may ask to see personal information we hold about you. As long as we can readily retrieve it, we will provide it to you. You may also ask for any details that are wrong to be corrected

**Privacy Act 1993**

This Privacy Policy is governed the New Zealand Privacy Act 1993.

**Contact Us**

To exercise your opt-out privileges, access your user information, obtain more information about this Privacy Policy or advise us of other matters regarding your experiences with LMI or the Site, please contact us by e-mail, post, telephone or fax. Please include your username and password.

Les Mills International  
PO Box 91137  
Auckland Mail Service Centre  
New Zealand  
Ph: +649 366 9900  
Fax: +649 366 9901  
Email: [info@lesmills.com](mailto:%20info@lesmills.com)

**Changing This Policy**

We may update or change this Privacy Policy at any time. We will tell you about any changes by posting an updated policy on our website. Any such modification will be effective immediately upon posting on the Site and your continued use of the Site following such posting constitutes your acceptance of the revised Privacy Policy.
